

BELMONTE ELIAN

24 YEARS

DATA SCIENTIST

PERSONAL PROFILE

As a Data Scientist and Software Engineer with two years of professional experience, I am currently engaged in a full-time role at Swiss AviationSoftware. Here, I have the privilege of contributing to groundbreaking **Data Science** and **Machine Learning** initiatives, including Al Predictive Maintenance and applications of Large Language Models.

I'm currently looking for **new challenges** and opportunities with a company that want to make data its major asset.

SKILLS

- Programming: Python, Git, Docker, SQL, Java, C, JS/TS, HTML/CSS, Dart
- Data Science: Pandas, Numpy,
 SKLearn, Tensorflow/Keras, PyTorch,
 OpenCV. PvSpark, Matplotlib
- Cloud: GCP & VertexAl, Azure
- BI: Tableau, PowerBI, Oracle BI
- Back-end: Flask, Django, Node.Js
- Front-end: Flutter, ReactJS, Angular
- Networking: Cisco CCNA1 & CCNA2
- Languages: French native language.
 English proficient level, German basic level (learning)

CONTACT INFORMATION

www.elianbelmonte.com
Phone: +33 6 67 22 22 09
E-Mail: elian.68@hotmail.fr
49 Rue de Strasbourg
68300 SAINT-LOUIS
Haut-Rhin, France

WORK EXPERIENCE

Swiss Aviation Software. Switzerland

Data Scientist & Software Engineer - R&D department (08/2023 - Ongoing)

- Develop multiple productive Cloud-based GenAl applications (Advanced RAG chatbot, Al Agent...)
- Evaluation and monitoring of GenAl systems
- Develop predictive models and advanced machine learning solutions in the aviation industry
- Design and train DL models with TensorFlow & PyTorch
- Deploy, manage, & scale ML models on GCP & VertexAl
- Full-Stack development in Python, Java & Flutter

End-of-study project in Data Science - R&D department (02/2023 - 07/2023)

- Time series forecast with LSTM, XGBoost, ...
- Model testing and hyperparameter finetuning
- Data extraction, analysis and feature engineering
- Development of APIs and Flutter apps for visualization

Sonceboz SA, Switzerland

Computer science internship within the I4.0 department (09/2021 - 02/2022)

- Al and data analysis with Jupyter
- Refactoring of the MES web app (Angular & Ionic)
- Design of dashboards and data processing
- Creation of web applications and APIs REST
- AR/VR Sonceboz Logistic System project (Unity3D)

Manor Food Basel St.Jakob, Switzerland Student commercial employee (2019-2021)

AMAC Aerospace Basel, Switzerland
One-month worker internship (January 2019)

EDUCATION

University of Technology of Belfort-Montbéliard Engineering/Master degree - Computer science (2018 - 2023)

Specialization in **Data Science** & **Computer Vision**

Scheurer Kestner High school of Thann Scientific High School diploma, High honor (2018)

ACTIVITIES AND INTERESTS

I practice running and take part in many races. I also participate in Kaggle competitions to become a better Data Scientist. I really enjoy creating new things and keeping up to date with the latest technological innovations.